You can't have a little bit of a problem
to get the same thing. And how do I agree with
you?
Singer?
Okay, um, before we go, ah, I'm going to discuss with you about active learning, right?
Yeah, if you've been, I presumes that, uh, you have a lady.
Watch the video. And I also give you four question, but now ignore the number, because that's wrong.
So one, two, three, four. Right?
So four questions. Um, what do you understand?
But conceptual? And talk. Want to answer chopin talk.
What do you understand? The concept of chopin Talk.
Have a good one. Good one.
David Chum Talk. Let me watch the video.
No, no call. How comes you got a message that you wanted to, you know, preview that?
This is the video. I-I haven't told cats.
So things, you haven't watched the video, and you you don't know how to say that.
UK. Have you watched the video?
No, no. Why? It is our train class, the UK, you know, train class.
Yeah, so, everything. So, going to post there, right again.
Remember, you know, next week, you got a preview.
All right, before you come here.
Um, alex, have you watched the video?
No. Why do you understand that?
Um, we have the video, but if anyone wanted to answer this question, shall we talk?
Okay, whether this is, what? Wait, wait a minute, or surpass the microphone today.
Okay, jump in talk. I want you to raise your hands by yourself.
Wait. All right. Um. Talking tom is a traditional way to teach students, and students have a real motivation to get involved in class.
Okay, yeah. Oh, what is the matter?
Chuck? Trouble is Echo Right. Okay, children Toy.
Yeah. So it said it's a traditional way, right?
And he said that students got no motivation.
Um, anyone wanted to add something about no motivation here?
You said to children, talk by using traditional chalk.
Right? There's a chairman talk. so I am the instructor, right?
I use a chalk and talk to get away.
And River said, there's no motivation.
What's that? 21. One, two. Answer this team.
Have you watched the video? Yeah.
Okay. Can you add something? Why says no motivation?
What does it mean? And would you want to add something?
Would you want to answer this?
Yeah. The same question is a traditional way.
Yeah. Is this a strategy student way?
A test megaphone
here? Okay, I can see that.
So if you want to answer, that's I'm with you.
Yeah, it can.
But now a formal method of teaching in which the focal point are the big ball are the teaching.
Voice Voice MHM And what we also said is just no balibation.
You understand that? No. Okay. Thank you.
Um. What's only here? Teachers. Boys.
MR That okay, um, yes, only Teacher.
Right. Then another team I volunteer students.
I'm no Motivation. Hello. Oh yeah.
Motivation is don G-U is. And why?
Student did have motivation? Because your talk show is a pathway to learning.
If you after learning, you will want to get more knowledge.
Uh, is more. Have have more motivation in this class.
Thank you. Okay, good. So team said that, uh, I mentioned that I keep learning, right?
So try and talk chopin talk.
And students have no motivation. And after learning, students wanted to learn more.
And I got the the driver.
You know, you have your internal driver, wanted to learn more.
That is a kind of motivation.
Something stimulates your thinking, right? Then it's going to respond that you need something eagerly.
That is the motivation. You need something eagerly, but yourself, that is the motivation.
E.g. you're hungry, you know, you want to eat, right?
Or, uh, you need to know something.
This is very interesting, like that.
You need to see that you have a drive internal driver, right?
That's kind of motivation, right? Alex, right.
Process on to addicts. Would you answer the 2nd question?
Similar in countries? What do you understand about some the concept active learning?
I'm gonna be really honest. I didn't watch the video, but I have learned the terms of active learning before, and it's basically a way of the teaching in class to engage with students.
So instead of the old traditional method, you're using talking toll, where the teacher just basically explaining everything using chop and just explaining using talk, but we're trying to create a situation in the class where basically everyone's got involved in the terms of teaching, and get a chance to, um, what is it like express their opinions, their thoughts and their ideas towards the materials that's being taught in class?
Okay, so yeah, it's a pretty good right?
So at least that, uh, I keep learning.
Well, he he knew the idea before, but you didn't watch the video, right?
But okay, if you understand that it's actually running, right?
Student is that every student got a chance.
Said that every student got a chance.
But, you know, even an opportunity, but you probably, you know, have no way to talk, but you have the opportunity.
I give you everyone opportunity, right?
So student had opportunity to talk.
Right? Since the talk, they don't feel, they don't feel asleep, sleepy, right?
And they don't more. In words, if you can convey a concept I in public, you need to organize your thoughts logically, right?
So the more you have this platform, the more practice you have that can reach your understanding.
Right? So after learning everybody involved in in the course, right?
The best way can enhance your understanding of the topic that instructor design.
So this is the one that in contrast, or how do you understand the concept of active learning?
Active, you are not passive, right?
If it's a traditional way, you will passive, receive everything.
I thought. Right? Again, what is the role of teacher in happy learning?
What do you think about the role of teacher?
Jim OK Pass this on microphone.
Okay, thank you. All right, the gym
teacher. So on the road of the
teacher in art learning is more like the top leader, or the people gathering our opinion.
Okay, so get your students opinion.
Yes, there are teachers
on as a guide, right? You have a coach.
So the role of teacher, like coach, you know, coach like your personal trainer, right?
So I-I think that's, um, well, nowadays technology very advanced, right?
So we have the advanced technology, then you can get a change information, almost everything from the Internet.
All right, so with that situation, you think that you can get it?
You can get all the information, everything from the Internet.
How come you need to come to the classroom?
So teacher throw should be changed.
All right, so not just the knowledge transmitter become a problem.
Sober, problem. Sober. I say that you come here with your problem with question, right?
So you cannot get this kind of convenience um from the Internet.
You. You ask no one, but the teacher can answer that.
Of course teacher has done. Now, the burden you got to study, you know, every day, because you got to answer question, become the problem sober.
Oh, your problem will be different from others.
All right. And since teacher are good at the topic, and he or she should have no the whole understanding, almost, right?
And progress with time, right? They can answer your question.
So become a problem. Sober, like a coach, the coach.
Your coach will be different from others, or the same coach will treat you both differently, right?
So there's a problem. Sober the year, the role of the teacher gathers students opinion.
Or, yeah, I would engage my listening to your opinion, you know, right?
So, even even though I'm familiar with some topic, but you have different kinds of problem, or your view points, they help me, you know, understand the level, or to what extent you have already understand this topic.
Then with that, then I can just my teaching strategy.
Okay, um. Those are role students.
My teacher become a coach like guide my problems over by not just deliver the knowledge information, not just that, because you can get everything from the Internet.
What is your room? Students room.
What's going to answer this? Okay, david Right.
All right. Pass us on. Goods.
Uh. As a student, student should express that opinion or feedback to the professor, then the professor will now a student give challenge or question.
Okay, thank you. Right. So students, um, come here, um, not just a listen.
So when I keep, um, participates in a discussion, right?
A students room in, excuse me to do a lot, right?
I said, that's, um, well, we have study roads, because in addition to come to the class, then I'm going to assign you in a discussion group, right?
And you need to share your knowledge.
Bye. So come here, not just the brink, everything, right?
So you bring everything, then you feel easy, you're not involved in in the course.
Right? Okay, so yeah, this, um, they summarize it.
Active learning is a kind of teaching methodology, right?
It is a new one, not that new, but it is hard to implement.
Because as a teacher, I need to prepare, right?
So I need to prepare based on students, no background.
Then I want to design the course, and I want to design the task, because the test is going to help you understand that.
So you might discuss in a group, right?
So I such as, I sign you in group
and I ask questions and then follow the question to raise out a question.
Right? So it is hard for brain structure, and for you, also harder because you got to prepare right both ways.
But you know, the beauty, the beauty of this kind of teach, right, is that
even more right you try, right?
You have some driven, um, this stimulus.
Then you said that, I I'm going to to read that before you come, because no otherwise you cannot participate in the discussion.
So yeah, that's explaining. It's hard to implement it, but we try, you know, they do that, but to enhance your comprehensions all around the course.
Okay, then the small bound to our chapter one.
Chapter one, right? It is an overview, because it's just beginning.
So the course, they give you the broad picture.
Right? So in this chapter, there are lots of issue, but I will not describe it in detail in 1 H We don't have enough time, right?
So there would be too big issue, right?
I wanted to focus on one is the STLC Right?
The 2nd one would be the methodology.
Right? We also have other the issue that, um, you can read it by yourself.
Seven, let's see, still see, right?
So system did better payments, life cycle, right?
Still seeing short. Okay, so we need to understand that, um, a system give birth, the birth, and then grow and decline, even die.
By all can reverse, go to the beginning again.
When you go to the beginning again, it's not the same because probably it's already, um, this the 2nd version, or probably you fix some problem, make it better, I guess, suits water to your knees.
All right, so we left cycle.
Um, in our textbook, we have four faces, but you may see other textbook of other resources divided into five, six, oh, seven.
So it doesn't matter about the number, right?
But they are similar, right? If, by somebody that subdivides a more, then becomes seven, right?
Or I put it in water like this.
So four faces the plane, the plane analysis, right?
So plan is a phase plan analysis, design and implementation by four phases.
Every face has its steps. So sad and activities.
And we need to know that when it's end, right?
So the end we have some, it could be documents, it could be code rang We call this digital because that deliver tells us that at the end of this phase, we're going to go to the next phase, and next phase.
So it is an official project, right?
So that's going to have I review, yeah, you reach the the compressions of the task, that it is a deviable, then can review it.
Okay, then go to the next phase that.
That's right, and so we're going to talk about methodology, right?
So here you can read spell the role.
So system analyst, and a lot of a lot of member in a team by yourself.
All right, we all have time to discuss the object of uentility, characteristic in detail.
I'm going to put data right today, we're not going to to talk about that.
And also, we
probably don't have enough time to to describe unify process, or U-P,
in short, unified process. Next week we also will describe the methodology or some processes, right?
Um. So we're going to touch that
again. The 1st ones are also give you key words, right?
So that help you on grasp the key issue, key feature of the contents?
Yeah, probably, I don't get that.
So, the formal process. So why do we need a formal process?
To answer this question, you need to understand what is normal, formal informal.
Right? So what is formal process when we talk about the words formal?
All right, so do you know that formal process?
Carbon from process. Why? What do you need from the process?
I'm just press What? Uh? It's a systematic way to solve problem.
Yes? Sub problem I was the difference between four more informal, a formal and normal formal and informal.
A difference between formal, informal, uh, I think formal health a more document.
So the after you got, after you leave the department, or some or your organization, or the best people can maintenance, no system, OK?
So it's a former one who have a document around, somebody can follow the love.
So this is a formal When I talk about a year, is that what we need?
You have the formal process for somebody can't in a revise on.
And when, when we talk about four phases, all right, we talk about plan analysis, designs, implementation, this is a formal one in the process.
Okay, so that is a formal process.
Then we know that plain analysis photo.
That's right, we understand where we are.
Right? Okay, so formal, formal process.
What do we need? Formal process?
Kevin says that we can't help some No, some way like um, provide documentation that we can rely on.
We know that will will we write that?
That's why it's a formal process.
We know there's a prime practice, so we have a lot of activity, all right, and we know that.
And it's a formal process. So, um, and uh, without that, become informal.
Right? So informal, um, listen. Informal.
Okay, informal. So what is informally?
Um, can we design a system?
Yeah, doing Okay, in for a moment.
Let me give you a hunch.
In informal is not not the regular way.
Um, can we design a system by whatever you thought, based on your instinct?
You understand the question Formal informal.
It's probably hard to answer informal, informal way.
So if you don't follow follow the the phase, then all the photos, some matter does become informal.
I know this. This matter, it's hard to answer.
That's uh, informal. I mean, we design a system by you imagination, you are intuition, right?
That's informal, right? We cannot do that, right?
We cannot use this kind of measure to conduct the compressing project.
That's yeah. Well, TB your name.
Media Formal and Jiang Great function.
Large formal. Qi Long Woman Shit outside your washroom.
So she is a formal informal position mirror.
And would street intuition? Woman Design equal
the usual woman. We invite welcome
this kind of imagination.
Usual. That's basically your unique structure.
All right, so you should go the form
Oh, you should informal thinking. All right, so it's why we need formal process, without any structure that we fail by often we don't even know the reason, right?
So by chance, I succeed, right?
Order, I cannot guarantee next time will be so lucky.
Right? So, yeah, that's for money for more, right?
School system is not intuitive, not based on your intuition, right?
So I'm going to do that this way.
And next time, you know, I don't know.
Okay, so that is, um, that will we need for more than this planning analysis, design implementation.
Probably go to go back to the planning, but it was not the same.
All right, so every time when we conduct this kind of transformation, it was not the same.
All right, until Sunday. Dad. Right, so the system is dead, then we're going to change to another system.
That that we're going to do it again.
So that is the four faces.
So the process consists of four faces, right?
And each face consists of a series of stars, and we're going to document it.
So we have the proof, we have the documentation, we have the code, or that.
That's So it could be document or could be, you know, a deck of code that there whatever is.
It desirable, we call it desirable.
That's the product, the the product that we can't understand where we're we right?
So it should be rubable to be submits for review.
All right, to prove, OK, I approve.
You can go to the next one.
So this is about deliverable, right?
And phase are executed, usually sequentially, without planning.
You're not going to design, right?
That that's you are now going to design and then do the printing.
That's That means that we ask a sequential way, scrituling in order, right?
This and next and next are sequential incrementary, irresibly, or in some other, some other way?
I am here an answer to two words by incrementary, we understand spiritually incrementary it already.
What does it mean? I gave you the key words.
Really. It's a wedding. It's no one that's really is absent.
But restaurants, it's great. Please, please.
Incrementary. What is incremental? Incremental incremental measurements.
Incremental increase, A decrease, more than of us.
Incrementally. Is it a value? Is it a value?
Everybody? Yeah, I value. So we at Bye, bad morning.
So the morning by at value, incrementally.
This is ready. It ready. Incremental.
Near weather. The right away, get right away is like, Repeat.
Repeat. What does it mean? Repeats year.
Um, it is a plan analysis, design and implementation.
Tell me the weather submits it is I repeat?
What does means if I use this brand?
And as this design implementation, what does it mean?
See, irritably, everyone can answer this.
Irrelevant. Okay, kevin, I get pass the song.
It relatively
ully.
I mean, after a one run, you finish, I still see you may your sister may have some problem.
So you got the next round, and you will repeat it again again, so it is iterated
forever. Okay, good. Yeah, yeah. As I said, uh, we do it again again and again, while this one, a lot of wrongs like loop.
All right, why should rope? What the difference?
Not like a cold. I will call to you the same.
But you, you readily go to the previous phases by angle forward, and then so backward and forwards.
So we do this a couple of times.
Let me see it relatively. All right, so yeah, system design, you know, as alecutor in the secretary window, the secretary, right?
But we go back, all right, irrevery, and solve a problem and go to the next.
And then when we have some problems, we going to go back.
That is only one track, but we can do it simultaneously, mother track, right, at the same time, right?
So you can see that's not just one track.
So well, I'm going to that, you know, that's, that's, you know, that's um planning.
So we should initialize our idea and why do we need to have this system, or why do we need to have the change?
So you have a reason right to justify the reason initialize your thinking about the system design initialization.
You got to have a need right, probably from others' request, right?
Then we need to understand, okay, well we initialize this thinking, is it possible to do that?
Here? Feasibility. Why is this feasible?
It is a doable when you come up the idea.
And then it's just feasible. Do we have enough money to do the project?
We need to buy hardware subway, E.G.
that? That's all right, okay. No pay for the, the, uh, the professional and other staff self is ability.
So at the beginning, we need to think that, do we have enough money budget to do that?
Right? And, well, what about our boss?
All right, what is supporters that has all this question?
Or, well, very important ones. Can we do that?
So, good. Think it is feasible.
And then through the its brain, it's a project initialization to this.
very important. So we think that, um, it.
Yeah, it is worse doing that.
And then so we can do it.
It could be right or wrong if you do it right, right?
So you do the writing and then try to make it, try to do it right, so do the right thing the 1st time and do it right.
If you have a wrong decision, no matter how wise you do, we turn out the wrong right.
So do the right thing the 1st time.
I do it right. If you go to the wrong direction at the beginning, no matter how good you are, turn out to be fair.
Okay? The year project initialization is the most important phase.
Most important not to have correct, correct concept, correct direction, do the rise in the 1st time and do the right right.
So that's very, very important, right?
And then you're going to recruit the member and start the project, everything.
And you you want to know what should be included, what would you want to have?
So what means the function, right?
So if that is feasible, it's a right way to do and you have enough preparation, then you know that what kind of function By sometimes you know it's going to do that.
At the same time, why not Really?
That
you not. You have to finish all the plane, then analysis, we can do it at the same time.
So
you need to know what to be included, right?
So what to be included, analyze it, and then can we do it?
Well, that's hard, right? So design,
even though we know that, yeah, it is necessary to have business system and we get support.
And your boss said that, still it, but it just cannot.
So how come that you have a good idea, but, you know, generally cannot do it?
So this one, you know, you wanted to, you know, make it realize that.
You realize that it's very, very difficult.
So it should be the the difficult one, right?
Design, you don't have the technique, you don't have the skill or know how, but you gotta know a lot of house that you can do it.
So that's a difficult, most difficult one.
And so until you have done all this, then implemented become easier.
All right, so implementation, I implement that.
I give a good design and implement that, and to see what happened, uses feedback and correct them.
So this is about, um, the Earth deal.
See? All right, so, um, what just that on?
I think you're already right. So, um, then I'm going to rich Face is the most important.
What? STOC Planning, right? Okay, good planning.
Yeah, we know that is the most difficult, most important one.
And a ring? Which? Which face you think that's the most difficult one?
A ring? Yeah, gentlemen. Alice again.
Goods. It's Max, which this is a nervous, most difficult one.
Nurses. Yeah, is a difficult. Relax.
Design. Yeah. Design. Okay, so analysis is difficult.
We want to know this back.
All right. And, but this is not the most difficult one.
Even we know this back. You don't know how design it.
You got carrots, I am, right?
Codes. So, max. So yeah, um, analysis is is a heart.
But, um, yeah, we we need to have a programmer, right?
This program. And I just know how the program knows how to integrate the function, right?
So that's the most difficult one.
And, um, we just talk about feasibility.
So feasibility as in printing face.
So what aspects we need to take care about?
His ability? Everyone is Jim like possibility.
Pass the microphone. Where is the microphone?
Feasibility? What is that about? Feasibility?
Um, I think we need to consider about technical feasibility and economic and organizational.
Yeah, okay, it's pretty good. So I said that, can we do it?
Can we do We need to have the know how, right?
So technically, yeah, we can do it, but sometimes you can do it, but you don't have the support right organization, right?
There is quite important. And do you have the money or budgets?
Right? So, yeah, yeah, that's very, very important.
Not like you a graduate project, you graduate, probably because you you probably have no budgets, but you need to do it right?
So that is quite different. I-I said, it's a real, real project.
You need to have a budget to support, right?
Salary, right? Well, it's a lot of things that, yeah, peace about this study.
Okay, yeah, that's good. Um, yeah.
Dense. Um, methodology. I said, that's, we copy st O-C This the 1st issue.
I said, that's, um, I'm going to focus on SDLC right?
Part of that I-I didn't, um, go to very detail, but read the textbook.
All right. The 2nd one is quite difficult.
It's the methodology, right? We also, we'll talk about this issue next week.
All right.
It's on different textbook
records. This book. Chapter two.
One. Chapter two. Yeah. Chapter two, yeah.
So we talk about the methodology
and process. So here, uh, we can categorize that it's a
process oriented, data oriented, after oriented.
For the three we go bits as one, processoriented, data oriented, after oriented.
It says data center is the same oriented orientation, where orient to the process, mean focus on process.
All right, center, same student center, learner center.
Focus on the no focus songs, students, right?
So you're the same, right? After, oriented to world up to we care about, after all, the meaning the same.
Someone knows, process oriented. So I know that process oriented, data oriented, data centered on Some of you might learn this for Darwin, right?
D FD Before this, for Darwin, evidence a data for that.
How much, how much you know, and how many of you understand?
Dear d that for seven? Lose your hand.
Let me know that. DVD No One.
Little fruit one. I usually will buy cats D-D fruit album.
Anyone knows that? Yeah, you do.
Process, yeah. Process oriented. Yeah. I like to see that.
Yes. Okay, so process oriented is that?
Ah, you have to, you have to follow every step.
You have to come quickly every step.
I like del C. Del C, like DB.
You have to follow every like, analyse and implement something like that.
You have to complete it. So you think our planning is a process, the processor, most of the spring is face.
It is one of the process.
One of the, the printing is one of the process.
Yes, of of this is one of the process.
Supreme analysis, design, information, we have more adjustment.
So film planning is a kind of process.
Is that that right? Process? Okay, yeah, we can.
Yeah, planning on it's about face.
How face going? Right? Screen sharing.
But here he says, um, yeah, does this sequentiary, but the process ofiented?
Um, actually, this means that by process oriented, we regard process function.
All right. We want to understand the function now in between.
So year I sat as the the even though you saw this data, wanted to see how data goes and back, right?
And from process, how process no goes.
E.G. Here we have this, we give it number, right?
E.G. this process one, we have, this is a data, data for data for from P one, perhaps because P too, right?
The data for is a process.
A process is a function. This function, outputs
become inputs
another process. We
might have this diversion, the same data list.
Data will use none,
right? And go to, yeah, you good for this?
Zero one, two brain. The one outs when output.
All right, they can debridge right to different process.
And that's well, probably scum to data store.
All right, we save it. But this is not all because if you only say it, we all rethape it.
See you. So let's so there will be data out right?
Go to other process or go to different You can go to different process, or even go back.
All right, E.G. the doubts though, will we focus right here?
That's the process for space. If this is the oh, I-I should, sorry, I should use one, two, three, four, five.
This easy. Two, three, four, five.
And we had different data, right?
I could go to a different data store, data store, but we focus on the process, how data flow, right?
This is going to different process.
And this way we also have them, uh, originator, right?
Yeah. This is the entity. We have entity, right?
It's going to pass the data to process, Right?
So entity, you said your fruit.
I want you going to see most of us process this external, external, right?
This entity an ear. That's the process.
All right, with great, probably wrong year.
All right, go to other entity.
Like think data it's going to provide to other entity.
So this is process oriented. It's a function we can drill down, right?
That's one, that one, one, that two.
Right? This one drilled until the terminal that will write code.
So that's the traditional one. Is a process oriented data the data center.
Then we focus on the data, even though you can see data.
But this is not data center, data center.
Use entity relations. Darwin. You're going to see how interaction between entity, so reality, it could be Woo.
Okay. Easier one. If we have to entertain anyone and teach you, of course, not just two many.
So you're going to see one to one, right?
One too many. Many to one.
You understand that the best relationship.
So we focus on that. So energy, you
got the name. So you want this one, you have a name.
if that students,
right?
An age, gender is based on what we need.
All right,
so this the attribute, the bus.
It centered. Right? We want to see the interaction between the entity.
It's one too many, many to one, or many too many, right?
There is a data center. What about article?
Reentis actually oriented. All right, after oriented.
Wanted to combine. So here we only see the the process, the step to drill down, if this is the function, um, make receipt or make payments, right?
Retreat down, two, that one, two, that two, Two.
Three. Or two. That one, that one.
Judo, right. Turn down. It's a process, but after alliented, we combined the process and data into one.
So you're going to see the object right after has a name and attribute and behavior.
All right, so become three parts object name, attribute and behavior.
We can find that altogether after oriented.
Then that's what I wanted to discuss and teach, right?
So after oriented, this is object oriented question for now.
Kinds behind the schedule. I take minutes break.